A Guide to the James Branch Cabell Correspondence with Carl Van Doren and F. Scott Fitzgerald, 1920-1926
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
James Branch Cabell Correspondence with Carl Van Doren and F. Scott Fitzgerald, 1920-1926
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5947-f
This collection consists of 36 items on 1 reel: positive; 35 mm.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited on 1960 May 20.
Scope and Content Information
In this collection of James Branch Cabell letters to Carl Van Doren and F. Scott Fitzgerald, Cabell thanks Van Doren, editor of The Nation, for his reviews of Cabell's Figures of Earth, The Silver Stallion, and Barren Ground; mentions revisions he is working on for Chivalry and The Line of Love; and discusses a proposed introduction by Van Doren to a re-issued edition of Jurgen. The introduction was rejected by the publishers. Cabell sends F. Scott Fitzgerald a copy of Jurgen and praises Fitzgerald's This Side of Paradise. Also included in the collection are two portraits of Cabell.
These letters are on microfilm (M-1530), from originals at Princeton University. They are in the order in which they appear on the microfilm.
Contents List
- Letter from James Branch Cabell to Carl Van Doren 1921 Mar 15, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1921 Apr 8, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1921 Jun 25, TLS. 1 p.
  [w/env.]
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1921 Oct 8, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1921 Oct 13, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1921 Oct 24, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1921 Dec 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1922 Mar 25, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1922 Mar 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1922 Apr 26, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1922 May 11, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1922 May 19, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1922 Oct 21, TLS
  1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1922 Nov 14, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1922 Dec 10, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from [Carl Van Doren] to J.B.C. 1922 Dec 14, TL. 1 p.
  [carbon]
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1924 Jun 18, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from [Van Doren] to J.B.C. 1924 Jun 20, TL. 1 p.
  [carbon.]
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1924 Aug 3, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from Van Doren to J.B.C. 1924 Aug 8, TL. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1924 Oct 25, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1924 Oct 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from Van Doren to J.B.C. 1924 Nov 5, TL. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1924 Nov 13, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1925 Feb 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1925 Apr 15, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1925 Apr 25, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1925 May 8, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1925 Sep 30, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1926 May 21, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Van Doren 1926 Nov 20, TLS. 1 p.
  [w/env. and photo of J.B.C. and clipping, re: J.B.C.]
- Letter from J.B.C. to Zelda Fitzgerald 1920 Dec 20, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to F. Scott Fitzgerald 1920 Dec 29, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to F. Scott Fitzgerald 1922 Feb 24, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Fitzgerald 1922 Mar 18, TLS. 1 p.
- Letter from J.B.C. to Fitzgerald 1923 May 5, TLS. 1 p.